A Guide to the Mantapike Canning Company Records, 1903-1927
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Mantapike Canning Company Records, 1903-1927
Library of Virginia
28049c
1.05 cubic feet (3 boxes) and one oversize folder located in Oversize Box 61
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of C.H. Oliver, 23 April 1973.
Biographical/Historical Information
Mantapike Canning Company of King and Queen County, Virginia, was incorporated in 1903 and ceased operation in 1918. The board consisted of R.M. Pollard, President and Director, W.B. Walker, Vice President, R.D. Allen, Treasurer, W.F. Bagby, Secretary, and Thomas Latane, Director. The company sold tomatoes under the "King and Queen" brand name.
Scope and Content Information
Records, 1903-1927, of the Mantapike Canning Company, including accounts, bank statements, deposit slips, bills, correspondence, invoices, insurance policies, cancelled checks, journals, and minutes. The correspondence, 1909-1919, includes letters to growers and canners regarding the shipment of produce and payment of accounts. Also included is a license issued by the United States Food Administration, 1918, insurance policies, 1906-1913, and tax receipts, 1908-1919. The records also include a minute book, 1911-1926, ledger, 1903-1927, journal of tomato sales, 1917-1918, and a notebook listing characteristics of various chemicals. See also Allen and Oliver Records (acc. 28049a) for related materials.
Arrangement
Organized into three boxes. Box 1 is arranged alphabetically by folder title. Box 2 contains cancelled checks. Box 3 contains minute book, ledger, journal, and chemical notebook.
Contents List
- Accounts, 1903-1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Bank deposit slips, 1905-1911 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Bank deposit slips, 1912-1918 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Bank statements, 1908-1917 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Bills, 1905-1920 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Contract, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1909-1919 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Envelopes (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Insurance policies, 1906-1913 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Invoices, 1917-1918 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- License, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Taxes, 1908-1919 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Cancelled checks, 1907-1919 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Cancelled checks, 1907-1919 (Box 2)
- Journal, 1903-1927 (Box 3)
- Journal of tomato sales, 1917-1918 (Box 3)
- Minutes, 1911-1926 (Box 3)
- Notebook listing various chemicals (Box 3)